<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shashank&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://shank4804.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Shashank&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 06:10:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shank4804.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Career transition to Product</title>
      <link>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/switching-to-product-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 06:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/switching-to-product-management/</guid>
      <description>Since Jan 2022, I switched careers from being an SDE to PM. I wanted to share my thoughts here on &amp;ldquo;Why&amp;rdquo; did want to switch careers:
What do I want to do in my career? As of July 11th 2022, I would hit 6+ years in Software Engineering career. I would have learnt a lot in semiconductors (Intel), SaaS (Workday), ML platforms (AWS). I would be at a point in my career where I have been good at how to build a product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://shank4804.github.io/photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 07:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shank4804.github.io/photography/</guid>
      <description> Photography I love photography. Here are some from my Flickr album:

 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Started a new podcast around tech, startups, venture capital</title>
      <link>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/started-tech-startup-venture-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 06:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/started-tech-startup-venture-podcast/</guid>
      <description>[Update as of April 2022] Shutdown the podcast because of following reasons:   Super tedious to edit / create videos + audio.
  Less viewership.
  Didn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy doing it anymore because of 1 and 2 where the feedback loop to do it further was not there.
  Learnings from running the podcast and shutting it:   Creating media content which users want to listen / view is pretty hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AngelList&#39;s Naval Ravikant: How to Get Rich (without getting lucky)</title>
      <link>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/naval-ravikant-how-to-get-rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 06:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/naval-ravikant-how-to-get-rich/</guid>
      <description>Amazing series of tweets on wealth generation by Naval Ravikant who is the founder of AngelList and an investor in a host of successful companies.
The podcast discussing these tweets:
And the link to the original thread of tweets:
Seek wealth, not money or status. Wealth is having assets that earn while you sleep. Money is how we transfer time and wealth. Status is your place in the social hierarchy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview of Google&#39;s Machine Learning Crash Course - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/overview-ml-crash-course-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 06:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/overview-ml-crash-course-1/</guid>
      <description>Helps do 3 things better for Software Engineers:
  Reduce time programming: Move from rule based program (logic) to writing programs where we feed it a data and we get results from it which are closer to the result.
  Customize products for specific users: Ex: Instead of writing two programs for English / French users, just write a general ML program and feed it English / French to generate language specific results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview of Learning How to Learn Coursera course</title>
      <link>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/overview-learning-how-to-learn-coursera/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 06:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/overview-learning-how-to-learn-coursera/</guid>
      <description>This is my notes from the course Learning How to Learn from Coursera
 Quick look at concepts consolidated from the course  Focused mode vs diffused mode 25 minute Pomodoro method Long term vs Short term memory Spaced repeated practice to move from Short to Long Sleep well Chunking Releated practice Mini-testing Recall Illusion of Competence Overlearning Deliberate practise Einstellung Interleaving Procrastination Procrastination as a Habit Habit made of cue, routine, reward, belief Initial start is hard Process vs Product Use auto-drive zombie mode (blindy do) Activity tracking before sleep for next day Pomodoro early in the morning Conjure visual images to remember General Problem solving:  Apply known technique Modify known technique Focused brute force thinking Diffused related thinking Repeat until solution   Exercise best method for brain enhancement Visual metaphor (Mud + JSON Marshall) More Genius less creative Imposter Syndrome perseverance = the virtue of the less brilliant Teamwork for fresh brain perspective Minitest benefit &amp;raquo;&amp;gt; Learning benefit Left brain vs right brain (focused vs diffused) Checklist to measure test / interview preparation quality Start hard, jump to easy (Focused vs diffused) Anxiety = Excited for test, not afraid Breath slowly   Week 1: What is Learning?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SWE big N tips</title>
      <link>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/swe-interview-and-learning-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 07:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/swe-interview-and-learning-tips/</guid>
      <description>I was watching through Joma&amp;rsquo;s video on his YouTube channel about a guy named Cyrus Xi receiving amazing offers and I think his tips on preparing / learning in general are worth documenting. So, here it is.
Video link:   His reddit posts:  Pre-FB: https://www.reddit.com/r/cscareerquestions/comments/b3w1gg/2_year_update_my_journey_tips_29_gpa_at_a_small/ Currently after getting Uber, Snap etc.: https://www.reddit.com/r/cscareerquestions/comments/9i0pow/graduated_with_a_24_gpa_1_year_ago_after_studying/  His study guide: https://workflowy.com/s/study-guide/RD5kZ682pWX5oxiE
Along the read, I found this amazing article on Career Planning. Seems it was originally written by Marc Andreessen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of UC Berkeley Software Product Management course (COMPSCI X418.1)</title>
      <link>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/software-product-management-uc-berkeley-ext/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 06:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/software-product-management-uc-berkeley-ext/</guid>
      <description>I took this course as a part of Spring 2019 semester coursework at UC Berkeley extension.
I see soo many engineers jumping on the Product bandwagon. I signed up for this to get a sense of what the fuss is all about.
UC Berkeley extension is a program from UC Berkeley where individual courses from various departments can be taken as evening sessions in SF or Berkeley campus. Seems like it is targeted for folks looking to learn a new skill or for a career switch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://shank4804.github.io/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 07:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shank4804.github.io/resume/</guid>
      <description> Resume   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://shank4804.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 08:24:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shank4804.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description> Contact Email: shank4804@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/shank7485 GitHub: github.com/shank7485 Twitter: twitter.com/sshank_ IRC: sshank
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Unit tests and Mocks in Golang</title>
      <link>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/unit-testing-in-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 08:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/unit-testing-in-golang/</guid>
      <description>I recently started writing some code in Go (or Golang?) there are lot of amazing things to explore. Its always exciting to learn a new language.
So far, I absolutely love Golang. If you are like me who likes C, Python and all this systems/low level OS stuff, you&amp;rsquo;ll get a feeling that Golang for systems will be similar to what JS is for the web. (+ve JS things :-) ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applications on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/application-on-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 07:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/application-on-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a world of microservices. With soo many companies containerizing their apps and scaling them using Kubernetes, it&amp;rsquo;s hard not to ignore.
To an idea of Kubernetes and to play around with it, I created this tutorial to install and deploy dockerized apps on a kubernetes cluster.
This tutorial has 3 parts:
  Dockerizing an API
  Deploying a Kubernetes cluster
  Deploying the Dockerized API on the cluster and exposing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim Auto Complete</title>
      <link>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/vim-auto-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 07:48:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/vim-auto-complete/</guid>
      <description>Get code completion for Python like an IDE in the terminal using Vim editor with YouCompleteMe and Vungle plugin. Similar to
 This is for Ubuntu Linux (Debian) based OSes. Steps to be followed:   Update to latest Vim. This is done as Vim version greater than 7.41 isn&amp;rsquo;t available in Apt-get of Ubuntu Linux.
sudo add-apt-repository ppa:pkg-vim/vim-daily
sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get install vim
dpkg -s vim | grep &#39;Version&#39; #should be greater than 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Relay Chat</title>
      <link>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/irc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 07:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/irc/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I wanted to contribute to an open-source project, I was told on online forums to contact the specific IRC channels to ask questions and start contributing. That&amp;rsquo;s fine. I&amp;rsquo;ll do that. But I never understood what was IRC.
So what&amp;rsquo;s IRC? Wikipedia quotes &amp;lsquo;Internet Relay Chat Protocol (IRCP) is an application layer protocol that facilitates communication in the form of text. The chat process works on a client/server networking model.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
