<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Shashank&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Shashank&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 08:38:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shank4804.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Unit tests and Mocks in Golang</title>
      <link>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/unit-testing-in-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 08:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/unit-testing-in-golang/</guid>
      <description>I recently started writing some code in Go (or Golang?) there are lot of amazing things to explore. Its always exciting to learn a new language.
So far, I absolutely love Golang. If you are like me who likes C, Python and all this systems/low level OS stuff, you&amp;rsquo;ll get a feeling that Golang for systems will be similar to what JS is for the web. (+ve JS things :-) ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applications on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/application-on-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 07:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/application-on-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a world of microservices. With soo many companies containerizing their apps and scaling them using Kubernetes, it&amp;rsquo;s hard not to ignore.
To an idea of Kubernetes and to play around with it, I created this tutorial to install and deploy dockerized apps on a kubernetes cluster.
This tutorial has 3 parts:
 Dockerizing an API
 Deploying a Kubernetes cluster
 Deploying the Dockerized API on the cluster and exposing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim Auto Complete</title>
      <link>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/vim-auto-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 07:48:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/vim-auto-complete/</guid>
      <description>Get code completion for Python like an IDE in the terminal using Vim editor with YouCompleteMe and Vungle plugin. Similar to
 This is for Ubuntu Linux (Debian) based OSes. Steps to be followed:  Update to latest Vim. This is done as Vim version greater than 7.41 isn&amp;rsquo;t available in Apt-get of Ubuntu Linux.
sudo add-apt-repository ppa:pkg-vim/vim-daily
sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get install vim
dpkg -s vim | grep &#39;Version&#39; #should be greater than 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Relay Chat</title>
      <link>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/irc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 07:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shank4804.github.io/posts/irc/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I wanted to contribute to an open-source project, I was told on online forums to contact the specific IRC channels to ask questions and start contributing. That&amp;rsquo;s fine. I&amp;rsquo;ll do that. But I never understood what was IRC.
So what&amp;rsquo;s IRC? Wikipedia quotes &amp;lsquo;Internet Relay Chat Protocol (IRCP) is an application layer protocol that facilitates communication in the form of text. The chat process works on a client/server networking model.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>